<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Travel | Travel Stories]]></title>
  <link href="https://amitbansod.github.io/blog/categories/travel/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://amitbansod.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-17T15:48:17+05:30</updated>
  <id>https://amitbansod.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Amit Bansod]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[bansod.amit@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Santiago | a Walk in the West]]></title>
    <link href="https://amitbansod.github.io/blog/2015/01/16/santiago-a-walk-in-the-west/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-16T03:14:50+05:30</updated>
    <id>https://amitbansod.github.io/blog/2015/01/16/santiago-a-walk-in-the-west</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On the first day in Santiago, I decided to take a walk in local areas of Santiago. The places where people of Santiago shop, eat and celebrate. The west of Santiago is bustling with local markets, old town and people.</p>

<p>I stayed in the Brazilian neighbourhood, an area between metro stations &ldquo;Republica&rdquo; &amp; &ldquo;Cummins&rdquo;. Being one of the oldest neighbourhood in Santiago, you get a real picture of the city in this area. It has some nice, old restaurants where you can sit, chat with locals and get to know more about them. The houses &amp; surrounding graffitis have a distinct look!</p>

<p><img src="/images/1.jpg" width="800" height="600">
<img src="/images/2.jpg" width="800" height="600">
<img src="/images/3.jpg" width="800" height="600"></p>

<p>The walk started from the Museo Nacional de Bellas Artes. The Museum, one of the oldest museums in South America, is known for collection of fine arts centered around Chile and South America. A good place to visit if you are interested !</p>

<p>I walked towards the west neighbourhood near the Calicanto bridge over Mopocho river. This bridge was planned by then Spanish corregidor Zañartu and it became a major architectural monument before it was demolished in 1888. One of the old shops in the area still uses his name.</p>

<p><img src="/images/4.jpg" width="800" height="600">
<img src="/images/5.jpg" width="800" height="600"></p>

<p>The first market was Mercado Central, though called a fish market from old times, it is now designed on concept of shop-and-dine where shops and restaurants are lined up side-by-side. The outer part of market has more shops and few restaurants. You will find extensive seafood here.  As you go inside, you find more restaurants beside each  other.</p>

<p>The restaurants are on expensive side but should be worth it as the raw food is supposed to be fresh from the market! I tried a dish called Pastel de Jaiba (crab pie infused with cheese). It was excellent! The price was around 8000 $. Other typical dish to try is Caldillo de congrio (Conger eel soup).</p>

<p><img src="/images/6.jpg" width="800" height="600">
<img src="/images/7.jpg" width="800" height="600">
<img src="/images/8.jpg" width="800" height="600">
<img src="/images/9.jpg" width="800" height="600"></p>

<p>The next stop was &ldquo;La Vega&rdquo; or the vegetable market. The market was quite full with lively faces on a Tuesday afternoon.</p>

<p>The vegetable market has a special significance with people working here. The sign “Después de Dios está la Vega” at the market describes the significance of this place. Pablo Neruda, Nobel Laurate from Chile, was inspired by the people working here and dedicated one of his poems to them.</p>

<p>People from all walks of life come here to celebrate the existence of this wonderful place.</p>

<p>More information here (in spanish).</p>

<p><img src="/images/10.jpg" width="800" height="600">
<img src="/images/11.jpg" width="800" height="600">
<img src="/images/12.jpg" width="800" height="600">
<img src="/images/13.jpg" width="800" height="600">
<img src="/images/14.jpg" width="800" height="600"></p>

<p>In the end, we tried Sopaipillas, a local delicacy you will find everywhere in Chile served with hot salsa sauce. I got chance to chit-chat with the Chef &amp; Co. The down to earth nature and welcoming faces makes you feel home!</p>

<p>They thought I am from Italy for unknown reasons. :D</p>

<p><img src="/images/15.jpg" width="800" height="600">
<img src="/images/16.jpg" width="800" height="600">
<img src="/images/17.jpg" width="800" height="600"></p>

<h2>Practical Information</h2>

<p>Santiago has excellent metro where you can buy point to point tickets for 640/700 $ (non-peak/peak) with unlimited transfers. To use buses. You need a bip card which makes sense if you planning to stay for more than a week.</p>

<p>Santiago offers lot of things to do depending on your taste. In a nutshell, hike to the hill Cerro Santa Lucia for a great view of the city, visit the Museo Chileno de Arte Precolombino to know about history of this place through generations, take a walk around Plaza de Armas area in the afternoon and spend the evening at pubs/clubs in Bellavista area.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
